<PRORULE>
            <PREAMB>
                <AGENCY TYPE="S">ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY </AGENCY>
                <CFR>40 CFR Part 52 </CFR>
                <DEPDOC>[IN146-1b; FRL-7411-8] </DEPDOC>
                <SUBJECT>Approval and Promulgation of Implementation Plans; Indiana </SUBJECT>
                <AGY>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">AGENCY:</HD>
                    <P>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). </P>
                </AGY>
                <ACT>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">ACTION:</HD>
                    <P>Proposed rule. </P>
                </ACT>
                <SUM>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">SUMMARY:</HD>
                    <P>The EPA is proposing to approve as a revision to the Indiana particulate matter (PM) State Implementation Plan (SIP) emission control regulations that pertain to Knauf Fiber Glass (Knauf) which is located in Shelbyville, Indiana, as requested by the State of Indiana on October 17, 2002. This SIP submission contains changes to federally enforceable Indiana air pollution control rules. The rule revisions modify the PM emissions limits adopted by the State in the 1980s which are part of the current Indiana SIP. The revised rules delete references to equipment no longer in use by Knauf and update names equipment which remains in use. Because the revised rules reduce both allowable emissions and the allowable emissions rate, and reflect current operations at the Knauf facility, EPA approval of these revisions should not result in an adverse impact on air quality. </P>
                    <P>
                        In the “Rules and Regulations” section of this 
                        <E T="04">Federal Register</E>
                        , EPA is approving the State's request as a direct final rule without prior proposal because EPA views this action as noncontroversial and anticipates no adverse comments. The rationale for approval is set forth in the direct final rule. If EPA receives no written adverse comments, EPA will take no further action on this proposed rule. If EPA receives written adverse comment, we will publish a timely withdrawal of the direct final rule in the 
                        <E T="04">Federal Register</E>
                         and inform the public that the rule will not take effect. In that event, EPA will address all relevant public comments in a subsequent final rule based on this proposed rule. In either event, EPA will not institute a second comment period on this action. Any parties interested in commenting must do so at this time. 
                    </P>
                </SUM>
                <EFFDATE>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">DATES:</HD>
                    <P>Comments on this action must be received by January 8, 2003. </P>
                </EFFDATE>
                <ADD>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">ADDRESSES:</HD>
                    <P>Written comments should be mailed to: J. Elmer Bortzer, Chief, Regulation Development Section, Air Programs Branch (AR-18J), USEPA, Region 5, 77 West Jackson Boulevard, Chicago, Illinois 60604. </P>
                    <P>A copy of the State's request is available for inspection at the above address. </P>
                </ADD>
                <FURINF>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">FOR FURTHER INFORMATION CONTACT:</HD>
                    <P>Randolph Cano, Environmental Protection Specialist, Regulation Development Section, Air Programs Branch (AR-18J), USEPA, Region 5, 77 West Jackson Boulevard, Chicago, Illinois 60604, (312) 886-6036. </P>
                </FURINF>
            </PREAMB>
            <SUPLINF>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION:</HD>
                <P>Throughout this document whenever “we,” “us,” or “our” are used we mean the EPA. </P>
                <EXTRACT>
                    <FP SOURCE="FP-2">
                        I. What action is EPA taking today? 
                        <PRTPAGE P="72875"/>
                    </FP>
                    <FP SOURCE="FP-2">II. Where can I find more information about this proposal and corresponding direct final rule? </FP>
                </EXTRACT>
                <HD SOURCE="HD1">I. What Action Is EPA Taking Today? </HD>
                <P>The EPA is proposing to approve as a revision to the Indiana particulate matter SIP emission control regulations that pertain to Knauf Fiber Glass (Knauf) which is located in Shelbyville, Indiana, as requested by the State of Indiana on October 17, 2002. This SIP submission makes changes to federally enforceable Indiana air pollution control rules. Indiana made these changes at the request of Knauf, and they apply to the operation of the Knauf fiberglass plant in Shelbyville, Indiana. The rule revisions modify the PM emissions limits adopted by the State in the 1980s which EPA approved as part of the current Indiana SIP. The revised rules delete references to equipment no longer in use by Knauf and update names of equipment which remains in use. Because the revised rules reduce both allowable emissions and the allowable emissions rate and reflect current operations at the Knauf facility, EPA approval of these revisions should not result in an adverse impact on air quality. </P>
                <HD SOURCE="HD1">II. Where Can I Find More Information About This Proposal and Corresponding Direct Final Rule? </HD>
                <P>
                    For additional information see the direct final rule published in the rules and regulations section of this 
                    <E T="04">Federal Register</E>
                    . 
                </P>
                <AUTH>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Authority:</HD>
                    <P>
                        42 U.S.C. 4201 
                        <E T="03">et seq.</E>
                    </P>
                </AUTH>
                <SIG>
                    <DATED>Dated: November 7, 2002. </DATED>
                    <NAME>Bharat Mathur, </NAME>
                    <TITLE>Acting Regional Administrator, Region 5. </TITLE>
                </SIG>
            </SUPLINF>
            <FRDOC>[FR Doc. 02-30938 Filed 12-6-02; 8:45 am] </FRDOC>
            <BILCOD>BILLING CODE 6560-50-P</BILCOD>
        </PRORULE>